so I want to see if I can start to tease
out what I think
he's calling these walks and what is
called thought and thinking and kind of
what's at stake and essentially what's
at stake right in philosophical thinking
right
so one of the things that people often
will say about Heidegger is they often
they often talk about first of all you
know almost everyone says Heidegger is
probably one of the most difficult
philosophers ever if not the most
difficult philosopher to understand and
to break into these incredibly difficult
to allow him to think your thoughts
right yet they all the often in the next
breath will say paradoxically however
that which Heidegger is talking about
right on another hand is very very
simpler and it's funny I I think I'm the
more I go into what's opened what
heidegger's opened up for me and I think
it's even more than Hydra I think it's
just not opened up for me he's really
starting to understand what that is like
what's at stake in genuine thinking
and what I don't mean thinking right I
want to really see if I can make the
distinction here because I think like a
lot of times what we call thinking is
not to thinking that I'm trying to point
to right now usually I don't mean the
wiggly things in your head that are
constantly telling you to tighten your
rectum until everything gets under
control thus making your rectum and
everything else and everybody around you
kind of numb with a weird forced smile
on your face
not that not that in fact that's kind of
interesting to think about that but what
you know what is that if that's not
thinking I think that's it that's it
that's a much longer walk but the I
think what what that is mostly is the is
the idling of social practices rolling
through the culture one of the ways it
rolls through the culture is it rolls
through people's minds lost in thought
constantly thinking right but it's it
that's not what I'm meaning by thinking
right a lot of that is just representing
kind of regurgitating rolling things
over and over and over and over in your
mind right now if we kind of look at
this and this is where we can start to
get into it now what is the basis upon
which you are idling what do you what
exactly are what's the basis upon what
you're thinking and idling you know all
those Wiggly is going on in your head
that are telling you to control all of
reality and to pretend like you're
having fun while you're doing it right
and don't let everyone know that you
hate everybody
great
so I want to kind of get it see if I can
start to tease out like a little opening
to see if we can like let it flash forth
a little bit okay so now if we just look
at the most basic thing in the world
right your simple being here beam there
right and so like imagine if if you're
watching the screen or if you're just
watching yourself watch the screen or or
whatever you're doing right now you're
seeing a world right seeing waves you're
hearing sound you're a voice in the
background
and you're seeing colors and hearing
sound and you're touching tasting
smelling all of your senses are are
bringing a perception to you you're
perceiving both internally and
externally right now another part of the
perception if you look kind of look
around is is that you also see that what
you're perceiving exists right obviously
of course because if that wave right
there or that water or this plant didn't
if you couldn't perceive it it existed
right well then that would that would
just things up right because if you
can't perceive that that rock exists
right the sky exists right there's a way
that everything exists it is the rock is
the voices the water is the sky is the
thought is including all of the
delusions about the rock sky earth water
all those delusions are
however everything that you can see you
can kind of quarrel up for the most part
you can correlate to a sense perception
right you can sense it but what about
this existence now you perceive that it
exists right obviously you perceive it
because it does it exists it's right
there okay so it's obviously a
perception but how do you perceive it
do your senses bring it debate do your
senses tell you that it exists I don't
think you can find the rocks existence
and it's in in the color of your
eyeballs or even in the rock so you
definitely exist see that everything is
but if we try to bring forward that
which everything that is partakes of
this is itself you're perceiving it but
you're not sensing it think about that
in fact the senses are based upon its
existence right the existence on some
level you could say is Grant's anything
to be colored okay anything upon
anything for you to see here taste touch
perceive including all of your delusions
about it
right yet
what is what is this is what is this how
do you exactly perceive it if you're not
sensing it
now on some level I think we're
automatically up to like a like a
presupposition that kind of a common
sense notion you know is that there's
this sense in which well obviously it
exists and I'm just looking at it the
guy look stop bothering me because look
it just exists therefore I can see it
but you can't see the existence well you
do see the existence but it's it you
your senses don't bring you the
existence right what is this existence
what is this this is we try to bring it
to the foreground
and you if we look at it like this if
you want to kind of kind of get a little
contrast here imagine that you know I'm
Christopher Columbus right and I'm in
the whatever 1500s and I'm looking out
or I'm an ancient Greek right I'm like
500 BC and I look out I still would see
things existing however would things
stand out and be intelligible and
present themselves in the same way it
did for somebody that far not that much
older another way of thinking about this
I was thinking about this the other day
of imagine Christopher Columbus actually
you know when he's a kid
he stands he stands out on the shore and
he looks at the horizon where he's gonna
sail his ship that he doesn't know yet
right and this is before that he
discovers that the earth is actually
round you know imagine he's a little kid
and he's looking out at that horizon and
then he goes and lives his whole life
and he discovers the world around and
he's like you know I don't know 80 years
old and he after all that and he stands
on the same spot looking at the same
view same time of day and he looks at
that very same horizon what does he see
that's the way distance discloses itself
differently that is you could say the
history of being starts to get at that
it's what seems self-evident and just
factual right they just innocently show
up and there you are just things existed
and you see them however yes but so what
we're talking about here is that it's
the intelligibility that it shows up as
anything at all and what grants the ass
is nothing just give it yet it occurs
just given and just that occurrence I
don't know if we can think of anything
closer to ourselves than the
intelligibility by virtue of which we
stand on and have everything just occur
in its ordinary average everydayness
boom there you are it's so close it's so
given that it hides in its utter uncanny
Ness
not what I'm talking about thinking is
about the basic question of what grants
the way the world worlds for you what
grants it's hypnocil
it's concealment into ordinariness it's
hiding in plain sight it's your ability
to fall from it forget about it
all of it thinking real thinking is
simply about you could say trying to
catch a glimpse of the very being of our
being as it withdrawals in other words
it's the matter all right it's like
what's at stake the very intelligibility
upon which anything at all shows up for
you as anything yeah so so that's the
thing I just wanted presents about
philosophy right cuz i'm i mean i am not
an academic by any stretch of
imagination right like but if you let
these questions if you let the question
of being really touch into you if you
really if it strikes you
you'll never be the same and some level
it's all you could think about in fact
it's actually more the case that it
becomes more and more that that is
always already been the case of that you
are the thinking of that even in your
forgetfulness of it and so what I think
I mean by thinking is drawing into and
becoming available to be struck by that
which is most near
to really listen deeply and maybe this
is another we can talk about this at
another time but I kind of can't tell
really the difference between thinking
and listening